还没全填出来?
Ain't working out for y'all, huh?
Mars是战神 对吧?
Mars is the god of war, right?
也是行星
Planet, too.
我知道是行星 但是提示是"希腊战神"
I know it's a planet. But the clue is "Greek god of war."
Ares
Ares.
希腊人称之为Ares 同一个家伙 名字不同 就是这样
Greeks called him Ares. Same dude, different name, that's all.
Ares正符合 多谢
Ares fits. Thanks.
不客气
It's all good.
瞧 上中学时我很喜欢这些神话
See, back in middle school and all, I used to love them myths.
那些东西很深奥 真的
That stuff was deep. Truly.
轮到你了
You're up.
州检请求传唤Omar Little 法官大人
State calls Omar Little, Your Honor.
兔儿爷
Faggot.
你是否愿意庄严宣誓 如实陈述
Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth...
全部真相 句句属实 以求上帝的保佑?
the whole truth and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
我宣誓
I surely do.
报出你的名字以便法庭记录
State your name for the record.
Omar Devon Little
Omar Devon Little.
Little先生 你多大了
Mr. Little, how old are you?
29岁 左右
About 29, thereabout.
- 你住在哪 - 没有固定住所 女士
-And where do you live? -No place in particular, ma'am.
- 你无家可归吗 - 四海为家 可以这么说
-You're homeless? -In the wind, so to speak.
你的职业是什么
And what is your occupation?
职业?
Occupation?
你以何谋生 Little先生?
What exactly do you do for a living, Mr. Little?
我打劫
I rip and run.
- 你... - 我抢劫毒贩
-You.... -I robs drug dealers.
你做这一行已经有多久了 Little先生
And exactly how long has this been your occupation, Mr. Little?
我也搞不清了
I don't know exactly.
我猜大概有8-9年了吧
I venture to say maybe about eight or nine years.
Little先生 一个多年来靠抢劫毒贩为生的人...
Mr. Little, how does a man rob drug dealers for eight or nine years...
是如何幸存下来 还在这儿为我们娓娓道来?
and live to tell about it?
我想是过好每一天吧
Day at a time, I suppose.
火线重案组 第二季 第六集 拉开序幕
The Wire S02E06 All Prologue
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* You gotta help me keep the devil *
"有白痴说自己与众不同 有什么用..."  ---D'Angelo
我们都查到了什么?
What do we know?
对于Sobotka 很少 他过日子精打细算
On Sobotka, very little. He seems to live within his means.
房子在Glen Burnie 车贷已还清 中等积蓄
House in Glen Burnie, paid-off truck, modest savings.
信用记录也没问题
Credit history is okay.
没什么特别的 也没什么可疑的
There's no flash to him, nothing dramatic.
听起来不像个金主
Doesn't sound much like a money man to me.
也许被他藏了起来
Or maybe he's hiding it.
工会也是捉襟见肘
The union is also a little threadbare.
工会办公室的物业税晚交了一年...
They paid the taxes on union hall almost a year late...
直到被法院扣押
and that was only after they got hit with liens.
看看他们的账本...
Looking at their books--
- 你传唤了他们的账本? - 不需要
-You subpoenaed their books? -You don't need to.
根据一起五年前在纽约发生的
IBS books are open to the Justice Department...
联邦诈骗案判例条款
under the terms of a federal racketeering case...
工会账本对司法部是公开的...
that came out of New York five years ago.
我们给华盛顿打了电话
We called Washington.
他们给我们发来了 Baltimore地方工会的所有资料
They sent us a copy of everything the Baltimore locals have filed.
账簿上显示只有不到一百名检验员...
The books show that there's less than a 100 checkers...
仍在给本地工会上交会费
still paying dues to 15-14.
从70年代的300名一直减少 工会损失惨重
And that's down from about 300 in the '70s. They're hurting.
那Valchek说的钱在哪?
So where's all this money Valchek is talking about?
码头工会这期雇佣了Bruce DiBiago 游说Annapolis州议会
The IBS hired Bruce DiBiago to lobby Annapolis this session.
并且通过内部干事和工会成员...
And through individual officers and union members...
在过去八个月捐献了约7万美元...
they've paid about $70,000 to various PACs...
给不同的政治行动委员(专为竞选人筹募经费)以及民主党团体
and Democratic organizations in the last eight months.
这在他们的账本中都有记录?
They show any of that on their books?
没有 我们是从不同的 竞选财务报告中整理出来的
No, we pieced that together from the campaign finance reports.
还仅仅是把工会干事的名字 进行了交叉对比
That's just what was in the names of the union officers we cross-referenced.
- 那钱从哪来 - 毒品?
-So, where's the cash coming from? -Drugs?
迄今为止
So far,
追踪工会电话并没有多少收获
DNRs on the union hall phones don't show much.
都是工会业务或私人电话 没有呼机...
Union business and personal calls, but no beepers...
手机和公用电话也很少
and not much in the way of cell numbers or payphones either.
街头交易呢 有联系吗?
What's with those hand-to-hands? Anything connect?
我们从许多白小子那买了不少
We're buying from a lot of white boys.
O'Donnell高楼区 希腊区 公园那边的高地区
O'Donnell Heights, Greektown, Highlandtown above the park.
但只是偶尔会和港口有交集
But any port connections feel random.
钱一定有出处
The money comes from somewhere.
也许和检验员的活动有关
Maybe it's what the checkers do.
我的意思是...
I mean...
他们监视货物在港口的进出
they monitor what comes in and out of the port.
这是他们的工作 他们的价值
That's what they do, that's their value.
是他们把东西运进来?
They're bringing the shit in?
或者放任自流
Or they're letting it happen.
就像装满女尸的集装箱
Like that can full of dead girls.
他们不让它被计算机记录
They kept that out of the computer.
这就是我们要悄悄侦查的方向
Which is why we're gonna quietly do some work on that side of things.
Kima和Prez
Kima, Prez,
我要让你们开始调查那些姑娘
I want you to start looking at girls.
没问题
No problem.
如果她们偷渡到Baltimore 那会是谁在操作?
If they're coming into Baltimore, who's working them?
是来做舞女还是做妓女? 我们需要深入那个圈子调查
Are they club dancing, whoring? We need to plug into that circuit.
你们剩下的人...
As for the rest of you...
Lester继续调查各种记录 追踪电话
Lester is gonna stay with the paper trail and with the DNRs...
找到其中与工会资金的联系
Iooking for connections to the union money.
Herc和Carver 继续注意码头附近的毒品交易点
Herc and Carver... you guys keep working the drug corners near the port.
Russell和Bunk Moreland警官
Officer Russell here and Bunk Moreland
虽然受凶杀科委派...
are assigned to Homicide...
但暂时和我们一起共事...
but for the time being they'll be with us...
查询码头数据库 寻找任何和走私有关的模式
running the port database, looking for any pattern involving contraband.
有问题吗?
Questions?
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 我是Thomas - Beadie
-I'm Thomas. -Beadie.
愿意跟我去Royal Farms(连锁便利店)喝杯咖啡吗?
Would you like to go to Royal Farms, maybe get a cup of coffee?
好吧
Right.
嗨 我是Thomas 你想喝杯咖啡?
Yo, I'm Thomas. You want a coffee?
听着 我是想讨她的内裤去做汤...
Listen, I was gonna ask her for her panties to make some soup with...
但是 我估计她会错意了
but I was afraid she'd take it the wrong way.
你声称当攻击者拔枪时...
So you're saying you were at the opposite end of the parking lot...
你在停车场的另一边?
when the assailant drew his gun?
差不多
Thereabout.
那你是否看见杀害Gant先生的枪手
Do you see the gunman who killed Mr. Gant
出现在今天的法庭上?
anywhere in the courtroom today?
嗨 Bird 你好吗?
Yo, what up, Bird?
为了记录请注意 你认出的是被告Marquis Hilton
For the record, you are identifying the defendant, Marquis Hilton.
对我来说 他就叫Bird
It's just Bird to me.
Little先生 你以前常见到他 是吗?
And Mr. Little, you had seen him many times before, had you not?
是的 我们一起蹲过监狱...
Yeah, we jailed together down the Cut--
反对 法官大人 我们能上前吗?
Objection, Your Honor. May we approach?
这个证人不赖 不是吗?
Quite a witness, ain't he?
街上的传言是
Word on the street is,
枪击发生时 Omar根本不在现场
Omar ain't nowhere near them rises when the shit pop.
这个小贱货当时正在东区...
Street said little cocksucker was over on the East Side...
抢劫几个Ashland大道的黑鬼
sticking up some Ashland Avenue niggers.
这是街头在传的?
That's the word on the street, huh?
问题是 String 我们现在不在街上
Trouble is, String, we ain't on the street.
我们是在法庭上
We're in a court of law.
法官大人...
Your Honor--
反对已记录并生效 Levy先生 继续吧
Objection is noted and preserved for the record, Mr. Levy. Move on.
多谢 法官大人
Thank you, Your Honor.
陪审团请忽略证人的前一句证词
Jurors will disregard that last comment from the witness
关于他上一次是在哪里遇见被告
in which he explained... where he had last encountered the defendant.
是或不是 Little 先生?
Yes or no, Mr. Little?
枪杀发生以前 你就认识被告?
Prior to the shooting, did you know the defendant?
我认识他 但谈不上朋友
I knew the man, but wasn't like he was no friend or nothing.
所以你可以毫无困难地
So you would have no trouble recognizing him
在白天 距离20-25码之外 认出他?
from a moderate distance... say 20, 25 yards in daylight?
没问题
No problem.
Little先生 你是否认出...
Mr. Little, do you recognize...
这把特别的武器?
this particular weapon?
是的 这是Bird的枪 点38口径
Yeah, that's Bird's gun, the .380.
- 你以前见过吗? - Bird总是炫耀它
-You've seen it before? -Bird always flashing that thing.
那么在案发之前 以及案发当天
So you'd actually seen it before the day in question.
你的确见过这把枪 对吧?
And on the day in question?
就在Bird的手中
It was in Bird's hand.
当他射向Gant先生的时候?
When he shot at Mr. Gant?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
Bird就垂涎这些蹭光发亮的小手枪
Bird covet them shiny little pistols.
反对 法官大人
Objection, Your Honor.
而且这小子轻浮到 即使是光天化日下杀人 也不肯把枪扔掉
And the boy too trifling to throw it off even after a daytime murder.
你就是个撒谎贱人
You're a lying cocksucker, man.
我要把你的心从你TMD胸口挖出来
I'll rip your heart out your goddamn chest!
被告要么自我克制 要么被强制管制...
The defendant will regain control or he will be forcibly restrained...
退出旁听席
and I will clear the court.
证人最后一句回答将被删去 陪审团不必理会
The witness's last answer is to be stricken and disregarded by the jury.
Niko
Niko.
Eton是我朋友
Eton is my friend.
大家朋友幸会 不是吗?
It's good to have friends meet, no?
Eton, huh?
在希腊语中什么意思?
That's from the Greek, meaning what?
不是希腊 是以色列
No Greek. Israeli.
是吗?
Yeah?
因为你看起来像希腊人 无意冒犯
'Cause you look Greek, no offense.
不管怎样吧...
Either way, I mean....
你有那些化学品?
You have the chemicals?
我可以搞到 要多少有多少
I can get them, as much as you want.
什么时候?
When?
我本打算这星期动手
I was gonna do something this week.
不过出了点问题
There's been a problem, though.
- 什么问题? - 我的表弟Ziggy
-What problem? -My cousin Ziggy.
他和东Baltimore的家伙起了冲突
He got into a beef with these East Baltimore guys.
一个叫Cheese的毒贩子把他的车烧掉了...
Drug dealer by the name of Cheese took his car, burned it...
现在说要是还不给钱 就要收拾Zig
now he's saying he's gonna dust Zig if he doesn't pay.
是的 蠢货一个 Zig把货搞砸了
Yeah, malaka, right. Zig fucked up the package.
那么你给我们带化学品来 我们付你钱
So, you bring us the chemicals, we pay.
你再去给他还债
Then you pay your debt.
本来是2700块 对吧
It was $2,700, right?
现在那混蛋说要加倍
Now, this asshole is saying it's double.
5400块 你能相信吗
$5,400, you believe that?
他先是抢走了车...
First he takes the car...
现在又要抢我们的钱
and now he's jacking us around on the money.
你需要 我们就做了他
You want, we kill him.
不
No.
- 不是要这么干 - 为什么不?
-That ain't it either, no. -Why no?
因为首先 的确是Zig搞砸了 欠了人家2700块
'Cause first of all, Zig fucked it up. He owes $2,700.
其次 如果你们杀了Cheese...
And second, you kill Cheese...
我们就和他的人卯上了 对吧?
and we're gonna have a fight with his people, right?
一年以后 走在路上...
A year down the road...
某个黑鬼看着我表弟 从汉堡店里走出来
some nigger sees my cousin coming out the burger shop...
在中央大道给车子加油
putting gas in his car on Central Avenue,
毫无疑问 准会一枪毙了他
no questions, puts a cap in his ass.
他很聪明 对吧? Niko 聪明
He's smart, huh? Niko, smart.
看...
Look...
我们没实力和这些人对话
We don't have the muscle to go talk to this guy,
去把事情摆平
make things right.
我希望你们有
I was hoping maybe you do.
Little先生...
Mr. Little...
我可否问一下 你为什么会为此案挺身而出?
can I ask why you came forward in this case?
我把我知道的告诉警方
I told the police what I know.
你有没有得到什么交换条件?
Were you offered anything in exchange?
- 比如说? - 你被捕过吗?
-Like what? -Were you arrested?
你有没有被控什么罪名 而作为出庭作证的交换...
Were you going to be charged with a crime, and by testifying...
警方将撤销对你的起诉?
did the police agree to drop those charges?
不 伙计 根本没关系
No, man, it ain't even about that.
成年后 你被捕过多少次 Little先生?
How many times have you been arrested as an adult, Mr. Little?
啊 我数不过来了
Shoot, I done lost count.
很多了吧 不过我懒得放在心上
Enough, though, not to take it personal.
非法持械...
Possession of a handgun...
非法持有藏匿武器 用枪意图威胁...
possessing a concealed weapon, assault by pointing...
抢劫 致命武器 又是非法持械...
robbery, deadly weapon, possession of a handgun again...
接着是违反假释规定持有武器...
followed by violation of parole on weapon charges...
然后是使用手枪
followed by one count of attempted murder...
构成一次蓄意谋杀的重罪...
and use of a handgun in commission of a felony.
那不是蓄意谋杀
That wasn't no attempt murder.
那是什么 Little先生?
What was it, Mr. Little?
我朝Mike-Mike的屁股开了枪 就是这么回事
I shot the boy Mike-Mike in his hind parts, that all.
修理了一下 他就不能瞎坐了
Fixed it so he couldn't sit right.
为什么你要打Mike-Mike的屁股
Why'd you shoot Mike-Mike in his hind parts?
Little先生?
Mr. Little?
- 因为我们有分歧 - 什么分歧?
-Let's say we had a disagreement. -A disagreement over?
Mike-Mike认为他该留着倒卖的可卡因...
Well, you see, Mike-Mike thought he should keep that cocaine he was slinging...
还有卖得的钱
and the money he was making from slinging it.
我则不以为然
I thought otherwise.
所以你打劫毒贩 这就是你的工作?
So you rob drug dealers? This is what you do.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你带着枪 走在Baltimore的街道上...
You walk the streets of Baltimore with a gun...
肆无忌惮地行抢
taking what you want, when you want it...
而当你的要求没被满足时 就使用武力
willing to use violence when your demands aren't met.
这就是你
This is who you are.
那我们为什么还要相信你的证词?
Why should we believe your testimony then?
为什么还要相信任何你所说的话?
Why believe anything you say?
你们爱信不信 真的
That's up to y'all, really.
你说你来这作证并不是因为...
You say you aren't here testifying against the defendant...
与警方达成任何协议
because of any deal you made with police.
没错
True that.
你来这是因为...
That you are here because you..
你想把在那个公房区停车场里
you want to tell the truth about what happened to Mr. Gant
Gant先生的遭遇说出来
in that housing project parking lot.
是的
Yup.
而事实上 你就是那种...
When in fact you are exactly the kind of person who would...
出于自身需要...
if you felt you needed to...
会在公房区停车场 开枪射杀...
shoot a man down on a housing project parking lot...
并向警方撒谎的人 不是吗?
and then lie to the police about it, would you not?
看 我从不把我的枪对准平民
Look, I ain't never put my gun on no citizen.
你不谈道德 对吧
You are amoral, are you not?
毒品交易里的暴力和绝望养活了你
You are feeding off the violence and the despair of the drug trade.
你从喝着我们城市鲜血的家伙那抢走钱
You are stealing from those who themselves are stealing the lifeblood from our city.
你是个寄生虫 仰仗着...
You are a parasite who leeches off...
- 就像你一样 伙计 - ...毒品文化....
- Just like you, man. - ...the culture of drugs....
抱歉? 什么?
Excuse me? What?
我有散弹枪
I got the shotgun.
你有公文包
You got the briefcase.
都是游戏的一部分 对不?
It's all in the game, though, right?
考虑到经济形势 怎么说呢...
And with the economy, what it is...
即使报价低10%或20%...
you can really consider coming in 10% or 20% below asking...
还是会很有竞争力
and still feel competitive.
即使是Hamburg街的?
Even on the Hamburg Street address?
是的
Absolutely.
我得承认 我喜欢1501号的那栋房子
I have to admit, I like the house at 1501 .
虽然我不喜欢在主卧卫浴间里...
Although I didn't like the color of the whirlpool tub...
水疗按摩浴缸的颜色 那是洋红色?
in the master suite bathroom. Magenta?
那只是装饰色
That's cosmetic.
如果他们想卖掉的话...
If they want to make the sale...
至少应该有点修养 把颜色换了
they should have some amount of couth to change the color.
我知道这事有点斤斤计较了
I know it's such a tiny point to harp on.
- 嗯... - 也许你是对的
- Well.. - Maybe you're right.
也许我们应该再看看 不应该随便就定下来
Maybe we should just keep looking. We shouldn't settle for just anything.
你知道这个星期天 会有别的房子要出售吗?
And you think that there will be some new open houses this Sunday?
抱歉 你说什么?
I'm sorry, what were you saying?
我们要继续看房子 周日你还能带我们继续转转吗?
We're gonna keep looking. You'll take us around again on Sunday?
没问题
Definitely.
- 好的 星期天一早见 - 好的
-Okay then, see you Sunday, early. -Great.
谢谢你
Thank you.
到时见
I'll see you then.
你就是一小孩 知道不?
You are a child, you know that?
- 想干什么? - 吃饭看电影
- What do you want? -Dinner and a movie.
得了吧 别这样
Come on, stop it.
为什么不?
Why not?
不会有结果的 Jimmy
This isn't going anywhere, Jimmy.
吃完饭看完电影 我送你回家...
Dinner and a movie, then I'll walk you to the door...
然后你告诉我 滚一边去 就像你当初应该做的那样
and you tell me to go fuck myself like you should've done way back when.
如果我告诉你 现在就滚怎么样?
How about I tell you to fuck yourself here and now?
那你就能省下钱 花在别人身上了
Then you can save that money for someone else.
别这样 Elena 别这样 我在你给的文件上都签字了
Come on, Elena. Come on, I signed all your damn papers.
再给我一次机会
Give me another shot.
周五 你付保姆钱
Friday. You pay for the sitter.
华盛顿那边怎么样?
So how that D.C. game, man?
和以前一样
Same as it ever was.
巧克力之城 我有段时间没去了
Chocolate City, I ain't been there in a while.
现在叫戏剧之城
Call it Drama City nowadays.
前者是Funk音乐在当地的分支  后者是当地方言里的"伙计"
不过 还是那Go-Go的老调 同一群老骨头
Otherwise, same old gogo. Same old Bamas.
同样的汤 回锅热了热而已 知道我说什么吗?
Same soup, just reheated, know what I'm saying?
如果你还需要什么帮助
If you need anything to make this happen,
那你得自己出马了
you gotta get it yourself.
我不能交代给我的手下
I can't go through my people.
Stringer Bell绕过Baltimore远道而来
If Stringer Bell reaching all the way past Baltimore
亲自送来这趟活儿...
with this kind of work...
看来真是够神秘的 不是吗?
then we got a real mystery going on, don't we?
别担心 不会出岔子
Don't worry, no mistakes.
不会有人回头找你麻烦
Nothing that might come back on you.
你敢对你的人打包票?
You sure of your people?
我堂兄在那边...
My cousin up in there...
- 他会搞定 - 好的
-he on it. -All right.
不过 我受不了那些GoGo的破调子
I can't stand that gogo shit, anyhow.
肯定没去过现场吧
Ain't heard it live, then.
在Oxon Hill有家酒吧 能把你爽死
I know a club in Oxon Hill that would wreck y'all.
好的
All right.
如果我路过
If I'm around the way.
那么 现在你怎么样?
So, how you doing?
正上护士学校
Nursing school right now.
不错 很不错
Good, that's good.
你瞧 Lester一直在鞭策我
Lester's been pushing me, you know.
他就是那样
He does it,
不知不觉中给了你动力
kind of without you knowing that he's doing it.
是的 我知道你的意思
Yeah, I know what you mean.
他说你今天要谈关于一些俱乐部的事
So anyway, he said that you would be by today to talk about the clubs.
关于一些姑娘 俄国姑娘
About some girls, Russian.
或者说那边的世界
Or from that part of the world.
那些来来去去的姑娘 嗯
The ones on the circuit, yeah.
你应该去一个叫Nightshift的地方 就在Holabird过去一点
You should try this place called Nightshift down off of Holabird.
我有个朋友在那儿工作
I have a friend who works there.
她去年和一帮俄国姑娘一起工作过
She worked with a bunch of Russian girls last year
大概有三个月
for about three months.
她会和我谈吗?
Think she'll talk to me?
如果我跟她打个招呼
Only if I ask her.
多谢 警官 没有问题了
Thank you, Detective, nothing further.
还有问题吗 Nathan小姐?
Anything more on redirect, Miss Nathan?
没有了 法官大人
No, Your Honor.
休庭10分钟然后结案陈词
Let's take 10 minutes and then run the closing arguments.
明天我将指导陪审团案情讨论
I have every intention of beginning tomorrow with jury instructions.
- Omar干得怎么样? - 没看到?
- How'd Omar do? - You didn't see it?
交叉盘问那段没看 到那么有破坏力?
Not the cross. That bad?
你的问题解决了
You have no problem.
解决了?
No?
开始他要你先付5400块 谈了之后
To start, he wants you to pay $5,400. Then we talk.
他说 付2700就好
He says, "No, you pay just the $2,700."
是的 我看见你们怎么谈了
Yeah, I saw how you talked.
但你不用付这2700
But you will not pay the $2,700.
而是得到被烧毁的车的赔偿
Instead you will get the money for the car that burned.
- 真的? - 真的
-Yeah? -Yeah.
他是谁我们不认识
Him we don't know.
但是我们认识他叫老板的那个家伙
But the one he calls boss, him we know.
你打算就这么撅嘴坐着?
You gonna sit there and pout?
我知道你不会认为 我去那个酒吧是为了看靓女
I know you don't think I'm going down to that club just to look at pussy.
我知道你了解我的为人
I know you know me better than that.
- 我瞧都不会瞧一眼 - 人人都会看
- I ain't even looking. - Everybody's looking.
那里的女的大多都是同性恋
Most of them women are dykes.
Cheryl 我是去办案
Cheryl, it's police work.
什么 这就能让我好受些?
What, so that's supposed to make me feel better?
Kima去街上办案去了?
Kima's out on the street doing her detective thing?
那该死的治疗
All that hospital shit,
那些康复训练...
all that rehab...
- 那些许诺... - 我们已经谈过这些事了
- all them promises-- - We talked about this.
不 你谈过
No, you talked.
你一旦下决心 我就说什么都没用了
I didn't get a word in edgewise once you made up your mind.
- 你去哪? - 和你一起去
- Where you going? - With you.
什么?
Excuse me?
谁知道呢? 也许我会看到一个 我喜欢的小可爱
Who knows? I might see a little something I happen to like.
那么那些都有着落了?
So all of that's on the table?
交通运输的预算里有了重建粮食码头的钱
There's money in the transport budget for the grain pier.
美国常用的城市公共设施项目融资渠道
同时发行筹集主航道疏浚工程资金的市政债券
Also, a bond issue that pays for maintenance dredging on the main shipping channel.
- 但是不包括运河? - 不 不包括运河
- But not the canal? - Nope, not the canal.
为此我们还要坚持作战 更长久 更深入
For that we'll have to fight a little longer and dig a little deeper.
所以 Frank
So says Frank.
我得说 为了我的钱
I gotta say, for my money,
如果我们能建起粮食码头 就算是有福了
we're lucky if we pull out the grain pier.
话虽如此 我们也是花了钱 争取了最好的结果
Be that as it may, we spent the money and took our best shot.
雇佣一些说客 做些明智的捐款...
Hired a couple lobbyists, made some smart contributions...
花钱做份评估报告
paid for a consultant's report
反驳一下那些环保争议
to argue against some of the environmental stuff.
是要花钱 但是也有了眉目
It cost, but we're starting to see it.
那钱是从哪儿呢?
So where y'all find the cash?
我一周抢两家酒馆
I've been robbing liquor stores, two a week.
说真的
Seriously.
说真的 我们从全国工会那得到点补助
Seriously, We got some help from the national office on this.
时不时地还会从各地的朋友那收到点捐款
There've been some timely donations from a few friends here and there.
关键是 至少...
The point is, at the very least...
下一年我们就能看到重建好的粮食码头
we're likely to see the grain pier back up by next year...
那意味着至少每年可以增加几百艘船的流量
which means a couple hundred more ships a year, at least.
- 如果 - 是的 这有个可恶的"如果"
-If. -And it's a big fucking "if."
- 如果那个狗娘养的波兰... - 嘿
-If that Polack motherfucker-- -Hey.
没有恶意 只要Krawczyk不搞我们
No offense. If Krawczyk don't fuck us
不把那个海景公寓大厦建在那里 对吧?
by throwing up waterfront condominiums first, right?
Nat说得没错
Nat's right.
隐患就是Andy Kraw或其他地产商...
The back door threat is that Andy Kraw or some other developer...
在最后一刻抢票
gets enough last-minute votes
否决掉粮食仓库的重建拨款
to sink the rehab money for the grain pier.
那些家伙也盯着这块地
Those guys are looking at that location, too.
所以我们需要每个人都拿起电话
So we need everybody making phone calls.
让你们的议员们知道 我们盯着这事呢
Let your legislators know that we're watching on this.
钱已经砸下去了
The money only goes so far.
现在我们得大声表态了 对吧?
Now we gotta make some noise, right?
- 吼出来 - 好的 讨论到这
-Make some noise. -Okay, enough talk.
你们有些人明早还要接船
Some of youse got ships to work in the morning.
- 另一些人还得去喝个够 - 我会喝个够
-The rest of youse need to be drunk. -I'll drink to that.
全国工会的补助? 朋友们的及时捐助?
Help from the national office, huh? Timely donations from friends?
当心点 Frank
Watch your ass, Frank.
- 就是这个? - 是的
-This is it? -Yeah.
从港务局那搞来的
Just picked it up from the port administrator.
这是什么?
So what am I looking at?
装有女尸的集装箱 被卸掉当天的Atlantic Light号
The Atlantic Light on the day the can with the women was offloaded.
这些长方体是集装箱
The boxes are containers.
这个被卸下来装在集装箱拖车上
This one's being offloaded and set on a chassis.
时间是10:31
Here's the time: 10:31 hours.
看见没? 被一架RTG重机移到L道6栈3排...
See? It was moved to Lane L, Stack 6, Row 3...
在10:37
by an RTG at 10:37 hours.
- RTG? - 轮式厂桥(起重机)
-RTG? -Rubber tire gantry.
所以从船到堆栈要6分钟
So from ship to stack took six minutes.
这是正常的时间 但是...
That's the way it's supposed to work, but....
箱号"AQQZ" ...
"AQQZ," as in zebra...
"396594"
"396594."
验证码 7
Check digit, seven.
这是装着妇女的集装箱编号
That's the container number of the can with the women in it.
看见没? 从没有被检查员输入系统
See that? It was never entered by the checker.
所以在计算机看来 编号不存在
So as far as the computer is concerned, it no longer exists.
Sobotka说这种情况 会在无线电频率被干扰的情况出现...
Sobotka says that that can happen when the radio waves get knocked down...
或者检验员输错数字
or when a checker inputs a bad serial number.
它在11:26从Atlantic Light号上下来
It came off Atlantic Light at 11 :26 hours.
然后在计算机中就再也没出现过
And it doesn't show up in the computer again
直到15:12
until 15:12 hours.
我在两小时后发现了它
I find it two hours after that.
一共近4个小时
So for nearly four hours,
它就流落在码头上 下落不明
it's out on the docks, unaccounted for.
Sobotka说经常会弄丢集装箱
Sobotka says cans get lost all the time.
一旦找到就会重新输入计算机
When they get found, they get put back into the computer.
你信他?
You believe him?
不 这次不信
No, not this can.
那计划是什么?
So what's the plan?
计算机的数据库...
The database on this computer...
有停泊在Patapsco所有船的记录...
has records for every ship that berthed at Patapsco...
从两年前开始
over the last two years.
我们要倒回去
We gotta go back through
找到那些同样发生了这种情况的集装箱
and find what other cans might've disappeared like that.
看看这里面有没有什么规律
See if there's a pattern.
一共有多少艘船?
How many ships we talking about?
几百艘吧
Hundreds.
我可没本事祈祷一下 就让案子破得不费吹灰之力
It ain't like I got a prayer of bringing this case in otherwise.
我就说嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
得了
All right.
- 你是怎么了? - 没什么
- What the hell is your problem? - Nothing.
嗯 你看起来像要吐了似的
Yeah, you look like you about to be sick or something.
我只是没法看她们
I just can't look at them.
Prez 你从没来过脱衣舞俱乐部?(Titty bar也是当地方言)
Prez, you ain't never been to a titty bar?
嗯 来过 但不是和姑娘
Yeah, sure. But not with women.
你确信你和我们谈话不会有麻烦?
You're sure you're not gonna have a problem for talking to us?
我才不在乎
I don't give a shit.
重要的是 你们是Shardene的朋友
You friends with Shardene, all that matters.
何况 我是从Westport来的
Besides, I'm from Westport,
我和酒吧老板已经把话挑明了
and I told them club owners straight-up...
在她们来之前 我就在这了...
I was here before them ho's got here...
他们最好确定 她们走了 我依然在
and they better make sure I'm here after they leave.
那么她们多久以前到的?
So how long ago did they came through?
上一批是6个月前
Six months back was the last batch.
我想是俄国人 但当你一句都听不懂时
Russians, I think, but shit all sound the same...
其实听起来都差不多 不是吗?
when you can't understand a damn word, right?
谁带她们来的?
Who brought them?
酒吧老板额外花钱招的
Club owner pays extra for them.
有个女的...她好像是个妈咪 专门负责钱
There was a woman...she was like the madam who handled the cash.
但我不知道名字
But I ain't get a name.
她也是俄国人?
She Russian, too?
她有点来头 也有口音
She was something. She had an accent.
这就像是前一天全是Baltimore的姑娘...
So it's like, one day all Baltimore girls are at the bar...
过了一天就都变成外国妞了?
and the next, what? All foreign girls?
大概就是这样
That about right.
这些新姑娘让他们赚得盆满锅满
They was making so much money with them new girls...
所以他们就让一些常驻舞者走人了
they let some of their regular dancers go.
我没有 因为...我的意思是... 这里也有我的客人
Not me, 'cause I mean, I got clientele here.
但其他一些人....
But some of the others....
姑娘们住在哪?
Where'd the girls stay?
让去哪就去哪 操 她们是非法的
Where they told. Shit, they ain't here legally.
她们什么也不知道 在这没家人
They don't know shit. They ain't got no family.
管理她们的男人总是跟她们在一起
The men they got handling them are always with them.
把她们从旅馆接到这儿...
Right there to take them from whatever motel they use...
再送回旅馆
to the club and back.
就呆在这 如果她们需要食物或者药品
Right there when they need to get food, or go to the Rite Aid.
她们和嫖客交易时 就呆在旅馆门外
Right outside the motel door when they up in them rooms with the johns.
有人试图逃跑吗?
Anyone try to get away?
操 我看见她们中的一个 被击晕枪电晕了...
Shit, I seen one of them get lit up with one of them stun guns...
就因为到街上买点吃的
for going down the block to get some dinner.
他们连上厕所都不让姑娘们自己去
They barely let them girls go to the bathroom by themselves.
而且当看到谁跟嫖客走得比较近...
And if they see one getting too close to the johns...
他们就把所有人转移到另一个城市
that's when they move the whole crew to another town.
这样她们就得不到帮助
Keep it so they don't get no help.
下一支歌你上
You up after the next song.
记下我的号码
Push my numbers then.
我要去挣钱了 宝贝
I gotta go get paid, honey.
需要别的什么 打电话给我
You need anything else, you can call me.
我会尽力帮你们
Help if I can.
我会替你给Shardene带声好
I'll tell Shardene you said hi.
她过得一定不赖吧 离行这么久了
She must be doing good, to be out for so long.
肯定钓了个有钱凯子 对吧?
She must've landed a rich one, right?
- 你是她女人? - 没错
-You her girl? -Yeah.
我也不会让我的姑娘独自到这来
I wouldn't let mine come in here either without me.
这里的娘们不是吃素的
These bitches in here are no joke.
13个
Thirteen of them.
在那面假墙之后 她们只有1/3的空间
They had about a third of that space hidden behind the fake wall.
几把手电 一点垃圾食品 一点水
A few flashlights, some junk food, some water.
只有一个移动马桶轮着用
A portable toilet they had to share.
稀薄的空气
And not enough air.
我定于下个月第三周进行宣判
I'm going to schedule sentencing for the third week of next month.
今天还有什么问题?
Anything else today?
法官大人
Your Honor,
我的当事人决定保留上诉的权利
my client, having preserved the necessary grounds for appeal in the record,
并希望我明白地指出:
wishes me to state unequivocally...
无论陪审团的裁决如何
that regardless of this jury's verdict...
他都是控方关键证人提供 大量伪证下的受害者
he is the victim of wholesale perjury on the part of the state's key witness.
我们希望确定上诉保证金...
We ask that an appeal bond be set...
以便于他全面参与此案的调查
so that he can participate fully in this investigation.
一级谋杀罪的上诉保证金?
An appeal bond on a conviction of first-degree murder?
- Levy先生 你别太放肆了 - 法官大人
- Mr. Levy, get a grip on yourself. - Your Honor--
我不仅不会做出交保待判的裁决...
Not only will there be no bond pending sentencing...
而且就我来看...
but as far as I'm concerned...
判决前报告也只是一个过场
the pre-sentencing report is a mere formality.
Hilton先生已被认定 犯有谋杀公诉证人的罪行...
Mr. Hilton has been found guilty of killing a state's witness...
那个证人就是在这个法庭做的证
who testified in this very courtroom.
他冷血杀人 以此敛财
He did so in cold blood, and for pay.
除非判前报告指出
Unless the pre-sentence report indicates that he is,
他实际上是救世主降世...
in fact the Messiah come again...
他有很大可能会被判终身监禁 不许假释
he will very likely be sentenced to life, no parole...
以使一个Baltimore法官 在他有生之年终于有一次...
by a Baltimore judge who, for once in his life...
感到在离开办公室时 他的工作是很有意义的
gets to leave his office feeling that his job actually matters.
Hilton先生 你是我们的救世主再世吗?
Mr. Hilton, are you the second coming of our savior?
- 什么? - 你是基督再次降世吗?
- Excuse me? - Are you Jesus Christ come back to Earth?
判决时见
See you at sentencing.
你也觉得不赖吧?
Was it good for you, too?
Little先生 这要轻于暴力伤人罪...
Mr. Little, this is good to get-out-of-jail-free one time only...
这张就是你的一次性免罪金牌
on anything up to aggravated assault.
- 多谢 女士 - 不 谢谢你
- Why thank you, ma'am. - No, thank you.
难得有幸
A rare pleasure.
该仪式性地眉来眼去一下
Time for the ceremonial eyefuck.
你等着瞧吧 你这畜生告密者
Come see me down the Cut, you punk-ass snitch.
我要把刺刀插进你的贱喉咙!
I'll shove a shiv down your cocksucking throat!
继续YY吧 Bird
You think on it, Bird.
坐牢时你就好好想着Brandon 听见没?
You think on Brandon while you doing that time?
我会收拾你的 伙计 我向上帝发誓!
I'm gonna see you, man, I swear to God!
- 去你妈的 我会像狗一样干你 - 你真看见他开枪杀人了?
- Fuck that, I'll do you like a dog. - You really see him shoot the man?
你当真问我?
You really asking?
在讨论小说"了不起的盖茨比"
但结局不好 那男人去了他该去的地方...
But it's fucked because the man got to where he needed to be...
而她根本不值得他这么做
and she wasn't even worth it.
你瞧 Daisy(书中的女主角)和其他娘们一个德行
Daisy wasn't nothing past any other bitch, anyway, you know?
他为她做了所有的一切
And he did all that for her
而结果什么也得不到
and in the end, it ain't amount to shit.
作者Fitzgerald说过"美国人的生命中没有第二幕"(人生不能卷土重来)
Fitzgerald said that there were no second acts in American lives.
- 你们相信这一点吗? - 伙计 靠 我们被关着呢
- Do you believe that? - Man, shit, we locked up.
我们最好别信它 对吧?
We best not believe that, right?
他说过去的经历一直伴随着我们
He's saying that the past is always with us.
我们从何而来 经历何事...
And where we come from, what we go through...
如何面对 一切都息息相关
how we go through it, all that shit matters.
我的意思是 这就是我对他的理解
I mean, that's what I thought he meant.
继续
Go ahead.
你瞧 就像书中结尾那样
Like at the end of the book, you know?
船 潮汐 所有的东西
Boats and tides and all.
就好像你能有所改变一样 对吧?
It's like you can change up, right?
你可以说你是个新人了
You can say you're somebody new,
你可以开始一段新故事...
you can give yourself a whole new story...
但是最先面对的总是 你到底是谁...
but what came first is who you really are...
而已经发生的一切才是真实发生过的
and what happened before is what really happened.
而一些白痴说自己与众不同 有什么用?
And it don't matter that some fool say he different...
因为唯一能让你与众不同的...
'cause the only thing that can make you different...
是你的做作所为 或是你的亲身经历
is what you really do or what you really go through.
你瞧 就像图书馆里所有的书
Like, you know, like all them books in his library.
尽管 他面对所有这些书...
Now, he fronting with all them books...
但如果我们从书架取下一本
but if we pull one down off the shelf,
发现没有一页被翻过
ain't none of the pages ever been opened.
他有所有的书 却一本也没读过
He got all them books, and he ain't read near one of them.
盖茨比 他就是他
Gatsby, he was who he was,
做了他做过的事
and he did what he did...
可因为他还没准备认清现实...
and 'cause he wasn't ready to get real with the story...
于是只能遭殃
that shit caught up to him.
这就是我的想法
I think, anyway.
抱歉 伙计
Sorry, homey.
你的审判结束了?
You done with your trial?
那好 我们把宝贝开出去
All right then, let's take her on out.
明天吧 明天我回来和你一起 Diggsys
Tomorrow. I'm back with you tomorrow, Diggsy.
你今天还有事做?
You got something else to do today?
是 还有点小事要办完
Yeah, last bit of business.
这才是你的事
This is your business.
这是退休生活
This is retirement.
今天过后 我就退休
And after today, I'm retired.
我让你开口再开口
Talk when I say, not before.
- 同志(俄语 非彼同志) - Serge 我的兄弟
- Tovarich. - Serge, my nigger.
- 你都瘦了 - 哪有
- You're losing weight. - Shit.
你都快瘦没了
You are down to nothing.
在这个国家 超市就是教堂
In this country, supermarkets are cathedrals.
- 我为你感到担心  - 你的伙计们怎么样了?
- I worry for you, buddy. - How your peoples, dog?
一样 挺好
Same, good.
你跟那人谈过那件事了 对吧?
You talk to the man about that other thing, right?
因为我可是会不遗余力地支持
Because I can get behind that business in a big way.
我们等会儿再谈这个 现在说另一件事
We will talk later. Now, another business.
好的
Right.
就是这家伙有辆破烂大黄蜂?
This the man with the raggedy-ass Camaro?
不是我的 是我表弟的车 而且那车不烂
Wasn't mine, it was my cousin's. It wasn't all that raggedy.
抱歉 Nicky是和我们一起的 可惜他表弟....
Sorry. Nicky is with us. His cousin....
但家庭是无法选择的
But family cannot be helped.
那还用说
Who you telling?
我有一堆混蛋侄子和媳妇的侄子
I got motherfucking nephews and in-laws
总是给我捣蛋
fucking all my shit up all the time.
而且看起来我没法收拾掉他们
And it ain't like I can pop a cap in their ass
免得在感恩节被抱怨死
and not hear about it Thanksgiving time.
说真的 我有一堆麻烦精要关照
For real, I'm living life with some burdensome niggers.
那么怎么了?
So what the fuck?
你要是没法付钱给我小弟Cheese 他就没法付钱给我 对吧?
You ain't pay my boy Cheese, and Cheese ain't paying me, right?
我不是说钱都要给我挣到
I ain't talking about all the money in the world.
但是Cheese不能在那街头
But it ain't like Cheese be in a position out on that corner...
让你表弟竖个坏榜样 明白不?
to let your cuz exemplify shit, you feel?
给你免了单...
The man cut you some slack...
很快所有其他混蛋白仔就会效仿
and soon every fucking-up white boy be on his titty.
无论如何 我们会付我们所欠的2700
We wanna pay what we owe. The $2,700 anyway.
很快我们就能拿到钱
We're gonna have it soon enough.
而你的人把钱加倍了
Your man doubled it, though.
他还烧了车
He also burned the car.
现在大黄蜂的售价是5100
Now the blue book on that Camaro was $5,100.
现在让我想想
Now, let me understand.
你坏了生意 还跑到这来
You gonna come up in here, having fucked up a package...
让我去告诉被你坏了生意的Cheese
asking me to tell Cheese, who you fucked it up on...
付你2400?
to pay you out $2,400.
他可以留着那辆大黄蜂
He gets to keep the Camaro.
这狗娘养的和你们有多铁?
Just how good a friend is this motherfucker to y'all?
Cheese 对还我钱可不会高兴...
The Cheese ain't gonna be happy having to pay me back...
所以我建议你们都离他远点
so I would advise y'all to give him some distance.
只要他不回头找我表弟
Just so he don't come back on my cousin.
无论如何 感谢你这么通情达理
Anyway, thanks for being straight on this.
白痴 要不是Serge在这...
Fool, if it wasn't for Serge here...
你和你表弟就都是它妈的干尸了
you and your cuz both would be cadaverous motherfuckers.
我查了移民局 海关 甚至国务院 一无所获
I went through INS, customs, even the State Department. Nothing.
时间到了 Jimmy
It's time, Jimmy.
你尽力了 对吧?
You did what you could, right?
是的 不管了 送她走吧
Yeah, fuck it, let her go.
今早就把她送去解剖室
This one to the anatomy board in the morning.
记下是无名氏
Jane Doe on the paperwork.
这不对 医生
Ain't right, Doc.
什么时候对过?
What the fuck ever is?
你把事情交给Avon...
You leave it to Avon...
他会帮你减几年刑
he's gonna get some years off your sentence.
我相信 Avon我了解
No doubt, knowing Avon.
一切都安排好了 D
It's all good, D.
就是露一下面 把Levy告诉你的说一下
Just show up, and say what Levy tells you to.
你到底出犯什么浑?
What the hell is wrong with you?
我在问你
I'm asking you.
那些掺了毒的货 是Avon干的
Those hot shots, that was Avon.
我要你回家 D
I want you home, D.
你要我扛下来 我抗着呢
You asked me to carry this. I'm carrying it.
这就是我 就在此地 就在此时
This is mine, right here, right now.
孩子 你没听我说 我告诉你...
Boy, you ain't listening to me. I am telling you-
妈 妈 还记得我们住在Linden大道吗?
Ma. Ma. You remember we used to lived on Linden Avenue?
记得那所房子吗?
Remember that house?
那时我6-7岁
I was about 6 or 7 years old.
我在门廊上玩
I was playing on the porch.
那两个双胞胎过来惹我
Them twins came by, started picking on me,
欺负我
messing with me.
记得不?
Remember that?
我使劲敲门 想进房子...
I'm banging on the door, trying to get inside...
你就站在那 开了门...
and you standing right there to open the door...
却不让我进去
except you ain't letting me inside.
而是让我回去 反抗他们...
You told me to go back out there and fight them...
无论是输是赢
whether I lose or not.
记得不?
Remember?
他们把你打得很惨
They beat the shit out of you.
是的
Yeah.
然后你跟我说
Then you say to me:
"孩子 也许是我把你带到这个世界上的..."
"Boy, I might have brung you into this world...
"但是生活是你自己的"
"but you the one who gonna have to live in it."
妈 我仍在这里
Ma, I'm still here.
我 你应该让我过 我该过的生活
Me. You gotta let me live like I need to live.
你告诉Avon...Stringer和Donette
You tell Avon, Stringer, and Donette...
他们所有人 别管我
all of them, to leave me be.
好了 娘的 我要喝一杯
All right, look, fuck y'all. I need a drink.
- 来吧 2002年的快看完了 - 不
- Come on, we're almost through 2002. - No.
明天又是糟糕的一天 对吧?
Tomorrow is another goddamn day, right?
是的
Yeah.
他们看起来挺饥渴 这轮算我的
They look thirsty, a round on me.
哟 Sobotka先生 劳动人民的朋友...
Yo, Mr. Sobotka, friend to the working man...
游戏高手
master of the game.
今天晚上我们在Annapolis 搞定多少票 Frankie?
How many votes we get down in Annapolis tonight, Frankie?
- 来这很久了? - 从毛长齐了就在这了
- Been here long? - Since my hair was brown.
我在和Chess说Benny的事
I was telling Chess about Benny.
- Benny 有兔唇的那个? - 这个有意思
- Benny with the harelip? - That's a good one.
Benny在打桩的时被卸扣砸了一下
See, Benny was working the hole and he got hit with a shackle.
一大块铁把他狠狠砸了一下 但是他对谁也没说
Chunk of steel clocked him good, but he didn't tell nobody.
直到他到这来
Not until he came in here.
那时"小鼻子"就叫Benny 去告诉工会律师
That's when Little Nose told Benny to call the union lawyer.
- Paul Sevel? - 是的
- Paul Sevel? - Yeah.
上帝保佑他安息
God rest his soul.
因此 Benny就打电话给Paul
So Benny calls Paul.
"我被一个大卸扣砸了" Benny说
"Me been hit with a 'ackerel," Benny says.
"一条青花鱼"?
"A mackerel?
"你又在负责冷冻食品?" Paul说
"You working frozen foods again?" Paul says.
"不 妈的 是一个卸扣"
"No, 'oddamn it, a 'ackerel."
然后他就撂下电话
Then he slams the phone down.
"那家伙正赶过来"
"'Other'ucker on 'is way over 'ere.
"他说他听不懂我的话"
"Says he can't undertan' me."
"小鼻子"问 "他干嘛来啊?"
Little Nose says, "Why he wanna do that?
"当着你的面 Benny也没法说人话啊"
"Benny don't talk no fucking better in person."
那就这样了? 我和Cheese了结了?
So that's it? Me and Cheese are straight?
是的 了结了
Yeah, you're straight.
这2400是赔车钱
That there's $2,400 for Princess.
它比这值钱多了
She was worth more than that.
Dolo 下一轮算我的
Dolo. One for the bar, hon.
你赢大乐透了?
You win the lotto?
如果我老爹可以 谁说我不可以?
If my old man can do it, who the hell says I can't?
你有病啊?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Nick 今朝有酒今朝醉
Nick, when I'm flush, I'm flush.
谁也不能长生不老 对吧?
We ain't gonna live forever, right?
下一轮算我的
Next round's on me.
我不喝了 先走了
Not for me, I'm gonna head out.
别啊 Frank 一醉方休
Come on, Frank, belly up.
改天吧
Take a rain check.
- 这个也是同样? - 这是第22个
- And that one as well, huh? - Makes 22.
都是Taclo航运公司
All on the Talco line.
都有"马面"Pakusa 在上面工作
All with Horseface Pakusa working the ship.
我们找到规律了
We're on it then.
你要给Bunk打电话吗?
You gonna call Bunk?
Moreland警官身体欠安
Detective Moreland is indisposed.
你和Daniels他们在一起?
You with Daniels and them?
不
No.
我们只是把计算机放在那
We just parked the computer down there.
我们就是弃儿 伙计
We're orphaned, man.
- 弃儿? - 是的
- Orphaned? - Yeah.
Rawls说的那话...
Rawls is talking like...
像是如果我不搞定那14个案子...
if I don't come home with 14 clearances...
我就不用再回去了
I can't come home at all.
Lester也是一样
Lester, too.
真爱在哪里 Jimmy?
Where's the love, Jimmy?
它妈的真爱到底在哪里?
Where is the motherfucking love?
嘿 伙计 不要
Whoa, man. Hey, hey
那你又怎么了 伙计?
So what's up with you, man?
没怎么
Nothing.
没怎么 哼?
Nothing, huh?
都结束了 Bunk Bird的案子是我最后一件事
I'm done, Bunk. Bird is my last piece of old business.
现在我没什么事了
I got nothing new.
就是一直想确定这人是谁...
I was trying for an ID on this one...
我也不知道为什么这么做
and I can't even tell you why.
我猜我是假装自己仍是一名凶杀组警官吧
Just a way to pretend I was still a murder police, I guess.
谁在乎了 对吧?
Who gives a fuck, right?
Elena和我要再给对方次机会
Elena and I are gonna try again.
- 操 - 我再也不想搞砸了 Bunk
- Shit. - I'm done fucking myself up, Bunk.
再也不了
I am done.
来吧 伙计 我们回家
Come on, man, let's go home.
好的 伙计
All right, man.
这边 兔崽子
Over here, shitbird.
你到底出什么事了?
What the hell happened to you?
- 摔跤了 - 几个跟头?
- I fell down. - How many times?
一起走吧
Let's walk.
- 爸 我... - 跟我走 Zig
- Pop, I'm-- - Walk with me, Zig.
投票对我们有利 码头明年春天就能重新启用
Votes break for us, that pier comes back online by next spring.
更多的船 更多的工作
More ships, more work.
好 很棒
Yeah, great.
你到底怎么了?
What the fuck are you about?
怎么?
What?
在一间坐满工会弟兄的酒吧里 拿张拿百元大钞
Is that my son lighting hundred dollar bills like an asshole...
在那装B点烟的居然是我儿子?
in a bar full of working stiffs?
搞毛?
What the fuck is that?
就是高兴一下
Just a smile.
- 高兴一下? - 是 高兴一下
- A smile? - Yep, a smile.
你想再揍我 爸 来啊 打吧
You wanna hit me again, Pop, go ahead, take a shot.
你从哪弄来这些钱的? 你知道你排不上出工的号
Where you come by that kind of cash? You know you ain't had the days.
决对派不上
Definitely not.
因为我老爹在工会里
It's 'cause my father's in the union.
我操
Fuck that.
先来后到 Zig
Seniority prevails, Zig.
这是保持会员忠诚的唯一办法
It's the only way to keep it halfway honest.
我知道 我没抱怨
I know, I ain't complaining.
我希望我能给你更多机会
I wish I could give you more.
你认为我不想给你更多机会?
You don't think I want to throw you more?
你给很多了
You throw plenty.
只是 上帝啊 Zig 如果我听了你老妈的话
It's just, Christ, Zig. If I'd listened to your mother,
- 她总是说... - 爸
- she's the one always talking about-- - Pop
- 没事的 - 你该去上社区学院
- It's cool. - You should do community college
像你兄弟一样
like your brother.
爸 不要
Pop, don't.
你想知道我还记得什么?
You wanna know what I remember?
想知道吗?
Do you?
我记得你
I remember you,
和Jerry叔叔 Walt叔叔 爷爷...
and Uncle Jerry and Uncle Walt Pe-Pop...
都坐在餐桌旁边
all sitting around the kitchen table,
说那些这个帮那个帮的破事...
talking shit about this gang and that gang...
谁卸货更快...
who's better with the break-bulk...
谁运货更快 谁偷懒
who could turn it around faster, who's lazy.
总是争来争去 对吧?
Always a fucking argument, right?
4个波兰佬 6种观点
Four Polacks, six opinions.
我记得你们到Covington码头
I remember when youse all went down to picket them scabs...
围堵破坏罢工者
at Covington Piers...
Jackie Taylor怎样被一辆警车辗了...
how Jackie Taylor got run over by a police car...
所有一切乱成一锅粥
in the middle of that whole goddamn mess.
我记得 场桥在风暴中倒了(Paceco是此起重机的牌子)
I remember when the Paceco fell during that windstorm.
你记得对吧? 压死了胖子Rick
You remember, right? Killed Fat Rick dead.
对 你还记得什么?
Yeah, what else you remember?
都记得 都记得
Everything. Everything.
那告诉我 "想当年"先生...
So tell me, Mr. "Back ln The Day"...
我们在这该死的半夜里 和这些码头上的耗子
what are we doing down here with the wharf rats...
呆在一起干什么?
in the middle of the goddamn night?
把我问倒了
Beats the fuck outta me.
每一个便条都代表
Every one of those Post-its
在卸货的时候消失的集装箱...
is a can that disappears... when it's being offloaded.
贴黄色条的
The yellow slips,
是它们装有合法货物 封条完好 并重新录入...
they show up again with legitimate cargo intact and are re-entered...
所以你可以认为这些是无心之过
so you figure those are honest mistakes.
但是粉色和绿色的再也没有出现
But the pink and the green, those cans never come back.
它们再也没在计算机中出现过
They stay out of the computer for good.
而粉色的 就像装有死者的那个...
And the pink one, like the can full of dead girls...
都来自同一家航运公司 Talco...
they're all from the same shipping line, Talco...
它们的检验员也都是同一个人  Thomas Pakusa...
and on all of them, the same checker, this guy Thomas Pakusa...
外号"马面" 都是在他当班时
he goes by Horseface, he's the one working.
你已经询问过他了 对吧?
You went at him already, right?
我们给他下了法院传单 但这个混蛋连眼都不眨一下
We grand juried his ass, but that motherfucker didn't blink.
要不要去厕所? 让自己清醒一下 警官?
You wanna hit the head? Get yourself right, Detective?
不 我很好
No, I'm good.
关键在于 我们终于找到模式了
The point is, we have a pattern here.
他们差不多把所有的资料都销毁了
What they're doing eliminates almost all of the paper trail.
只要他们能使卡车通过出口通道...
As long as they can get a truck past the outbound lanes...
有很多办法可以做到这一点
and there's a dozen ways to do that,
剩下的就只有计算机里的蛛丝马迹了
the only thing they leave behind is a little telltale in the computer.
一个集装箱从船上卸下来
A box comes off the ship,
露一下头 一闪就不见了
flashes for a few moments and blip then it's gone.
我们的目标应该是Sobotka 对吧?
Our target is supposed to be Sobotka, right?
我说 案卷是这么写的
I mean, on paper anyway.
你是在告诉我 他要真是Bunk找的凶手
What you're telling me is that it's better than a fair bet...
要就查得太值了
that he actually is a target in Bunk's murders.
也许我们可以和你并案调查 队长
Maybe we can fold our investigation into yours, Lieutenant.
把我和那14起也许永远 破不了的案子绑在一起?
And put my ass in the air with 14 open homicides that might never clear?
头们不会因此指责你的
The bosses wouldn't blame you for that.
我也没法再出头了
I wouldn't shine either.
我想通过这个专案组  建立一支特案侦缉队
I'm using what we do with this detail to get a major case squad going.
我带着这些悬案上马
I come up out of here with all those open files,
听起来可不妙
it doesn't smell as sweet.
那么下一步是什么?
So what's the next move on this?
我们复制这台计算机
We clone the computer
开始时时监控码头上的活动
and start watching what's happening on the docks in real time.
操
Shit.
D
D.
哟 D
Yo, D.
只是葡萄酒 嗯?
Just wine, huh?
我再也不多喝了
I'm not drinking much anymore.
不喝威士忌了?
No Jameson's?
也许之后再和女招待搞一下
Maybe a quick fuck with the waitress, then.
好的 我活该...
Okay, I deserve that one, too...
即使那事我也没再多干
even though I'm not doing much of that anymore either.
- 还有什么? - 抱歉
- Anything else? - I'm sorry.
我不知道为什么还要抱怨 都一年了
I don't know where it still comes from. It's been a year.
你有理由生气
You deserve to be angry.
有什么意思呢
What's the point, though?
工作怎么样?
How's work?
什么 我们要谈论 我生活中一切使你上火的事?
What, so we talk about everything in my life that pisses you off?
酗酒 女人 工作?
Drinking, women, the work?
只是想找个话题
Just trying to make conversation.
我退休了
I retired.
什么?
Excuse me?
只有船 没尸体
It's boats, not bodies.
天气好时 我捉螃蟹数海鸥
On a good day, I catch crabs and count seagulls.
- 这不是你 - 这不是我
- That's not you. - It wasn't me.
过去不醉酒 不鬼混就不是我
It wasn't me not to drink, or dog around either.
很多事都不是现在的我了
A lot of things weren't me.
我想再有一次机会
I want another chance.
改成临别一炮如何?
How about a fuck for the road instead?
- 怎么样? - 挺好
- How you doing? - Okay.
你把这些卸下来 车头和拖车都丢掉
You unload this, you gotta ditch trucks and trailers both.
伪装成劫车 好吗?
Make it look like it was a hijack, all right?
Niko
Niko.
如果你需要 我可以直接付你钱...
If you want, I will pay you straight...
或者 Eton可以付海洛因给你
or Eton can pay in heroin.
批发价
Wholesale.
把它卖掉 你可以挣到六 七万
Turn it around, you can make $60,000 or $70,000.
Nicky 他的提议
Nicky, he's offering, like,
可以赚3-4倍
three, four times the value.
我不干这个
I'm out on this.
Nick 即使我们卖给"麦克白"...
Nick, even if we walk it up to White Mike...
我们也能赚3万到3万5
we can make $30,000 or $35,000.
Nicky 来吧 伙计
Nicky, come on, man.
一半钱 一半粉
Half in cash, half in dope.
Nicky 我可以卖出去 没问题
Nicky, I can turn that package around, no problem.
- 不 Zig 我来做 - Nicky 你不知道...
- No, Zig, I got it. - Nicky, you don't know--
你听见我说的? 我说我来做
You hear me? I said I fucking got this one.
留在家里看卡通吧
Stay at home and watch cartoons.
为了我们俩 这烂事我来搞定 好吧?
Let me handle this shit for the both of us, all right?
你走着回家还是咋地?
You fucking walking home or what?
嗨 妞儿
Hey, girl.
- 我们今天干什么? - 我?
- What do we do with the day? - Me?
我得从保姆那把孩子接回来
I gotta pick up the boys from the sitter.
好的 不错
Okay, great.
他们得回到这 Michael下午要学钢琴
They're gonna be coming back here. Michael has piano this afternoon.
没问题 我们之后可以干点什么
No problem, we'll do something after that.
也许我们可以路过我那 取点东西回来
Maybe we go by my place, pick up some things.
我不想孩子们知道你在这
I don't want the boys to know that you were here.
让他们又开始觉得有希望
It's gonna get them hoping.
那么
So
你得离开
you need to leave.
看看都成什么样了
Look at this sorry shit.
这些混蛋对免费的东西从不珍惜
Motherfuckers not appreciate nothing that comes to them free.
我把它拿到后面去 也许可以用胶布把它粘好
I'll take it in the back. Maybe they got some duct tape to fix it.
D 对吗?
D, right?
是的 你不能进来 伙计
Yeah. You can't be in here now, man.
哟 伙计 你们这周有进Final Call(一份芝加哥报纸)吗
Yo, man, y'all get any final calls this week, yo?
- 是的 我们来了几期 - 外面没看见
- Yeah, we got some. - I didn't see any out there.
好的 等我一下
All right, give me a minute.
我很快搞好这边 然后给你拿一份
Let me finish up right here real quick, and I'll go and get one for you.
- 嗨 你好 - 怎么了?
- Hey, y'all. - What's up?
我知道你拿了我该死的烟
I know you got my motherfucking cigs, yo.
- 你想我戒烟 是吗 - 哪有
- You trying to curb me, yo? - Come on.
这里头是啥?
What's in there?